# Nicholas P. Mikstas

(408)460-2192 <u>nmikstas@alumni.scu.edu</u> https://nmikstas.github.io/portfolio/ https://github.com/nmikstas

## **Career Profile**

Full stack web developer with a strong background in electronics, computer science and electrical engineering spanning both private and military sectors provides capabilities in analytic reasoning that few can match. Earned a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Utah, with skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js and responsive web design that enhance existing proficiencies in areas including microcontrollers, sensors and FPGAs. Experience as a project leader has given the opportunity to excel in fast paced, high profile environments. Knowledge in both software and hardware give unique insight into the big picture for large scale engineering projects.

#### **Relevant Skills**

-JavaScript -C, C++ -Express -HTML, CSS -Node -Mongo, MySQL -API Implementation -React -Firebase

#### **Career History**

## Self Employed, Mikstas Industries, LLC, May 2019-Present

• Perform contract work primarily based on embedded systems

#### FPGA Design Engineer 3, L3 Communications, Feb 2018-May 2019

- Implement FPGA based modem designs in VHDL and simulate those designs in Modelsim
- Perform lab testing on products under development with signal generators, spectrum analyzers and other RF test
  equipment
- Write software to automate modem test procedures using C#

#### Teacher's Assistant-Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Aug 2015-Dec 2017

- Taught lab classes for Intro to Logic Design, Advanced Logic Design and Computer Architecture
- Taught lecture classes for Junior Project Design and Senior Project Design
- Created design projects for juniors involving PCB design, hand soldering and enclosure design
- Guided electrical engineering seniors through their year-long senior design projects by providing technical support and progress evaluations

#### Crit. Facilities Tech., Brookfield (Contracted to Apple), Sunnyvale, CA, Jan 2015-Jun 2016

- Performed various daily checks to ensure the reliable operation at Apple critical facilities
- Installed AC electrical power circuits in both lab and office environments

## Customer Engineer Level 4, Liebert, San Francisco Bay Area, CA, Feb 2001-Jan 2015

- Most junior Liebert associate to earn the position of project leader
- Consistently demonstrated the ability to work with both Liebert associates and customers of all personality types
- Responsible for coordinating large computer power equipment installations and startups located across the San Francisco Bay Area and other Western States, in many cases exceeding one million dollars in value to both the customer and Liebert
- In depth knowledge of three phase power equipment including rectifiers, inverters, static transfer switches, flywheels, DC power plants, and power distribution equipment

## Active Duty Army, United States Army, Iraq, 2004–2005

642<sup>nd</sup> Aviation Support Battalion, 2 Army Commendation Medals

# Army National Guard, Atascadero, CA, 1999-2007

• 340th Forward Support Battalion

# **Education**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, University of Utah, Feb 2020 Masters in Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Dec 2017

Graduated with Distinction, 3.8+ GPA

# Certificate in Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering, Santa Clara University, Jun 2015 Professional Certificates, University of California Santa Cruz, Extension

- VLSI Engineering, Jun 2013
- Linux Programming, Mar 2012, with Honors
- Embedded Systems, Dec 2011, with Honors

# Bachelors in Computer Science, New York Institute of Technology, Mar 2010

Graduated Summa Cum Laude, 3.9+ GPA

Associates in Physical Science, Salt Lake Community College, Aug 1998